<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Horizournal</title><description>Personal Blogs and Thoughts</description><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/</link><item><title>Standards in Geo-AI: STAC-MLM, OGC TrainingDML-AI, and Related Initiatives</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/standards-in-geoai/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/standards-in-geoai/</guid><description>Geospatial AI has rapidly grown, with applications ranging from land-cover mapping to disaster damage assessment. However, a historical lack of standards for organizing training data and models has led to fragmented practices. In recent years, multiple initiatives have emerged to improve the FAIR (Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, Reusable) principles in GeoAI by standardizing how datasets and models are described and shared.</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Working with RADAR : Case Study in Jajarkot EarthQuake</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/radar-image-tutorial/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/radar-image-tutorial/</guid><description>Step by Step tutorial to work with Sentinel 1 RADAR image with preprocessing analysis in my case study.The goal of this tutorial is to share my experience and steps I followed when I tried to work with Sentinel-1 Radar Data to findout the displacement caused by the earthquake in Nepal.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Opensource alternative of ESRI Story Map</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/open-source-story-map/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/open-source-story-map/</guid><description>Hi , As we all know how much we love Open Source and most of my posts are related to open source , today I am writing the open source alternatives I found and created for the ESRI Story Map . Nowadays story maps are popular specially due to their ease of use and people who love map and would absolutely thrilled to tell a story from it .</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I joined masters ! GeoData Science and GeoAI (AI4EO)</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/i-joined-masters/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/i-joined-masters/</guid><description>I am excited to share that I have started my Master&apos;s program in GeoData Science and GeoAI (AI4EO) as part of the Copernicus Masters in Digital Earth. This is a big step for me, and I want to tell you all about it.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Process multiband rasters (Sentinel-2) with h3 index and create indices</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/process-multiband-rasters-with-h3/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/process-multiband-rasters-with-h3/</guid><description>In this blog we will talk about how we can process multiband raster and create indices with ease. We will be using sentinel-2 image and create NDVI from the processed h3 cells and visualize the results</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raster Analysis Using Uber h3 indexes and PostgreSQL</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/raster-analysis-using-h3-indexes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/raster-analysis-using-h3-indexes/</guid><description>In this blog we will talk about how we can do Raster analysis with ease using h3 indexes and as a bonus we will also talk about how it can be served as vector tiles and display on the map</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring Overture Data</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/exploring-overture-data/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/exploring-overture-data/</guid><description>Welcome ! First lets start with overture , if you don&apos;t know what is  Overture Maps Foundation and what it does I strongly recommend you to go through this website : https://overturemaps.org/ , I tried to build small utilities and hosted them so that readers of this blog also can look into the data and analyze by themselves.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Install latest gdal in Debian</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/install-latest-gdal-in-debian/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/install-latest-gdal-in-debian/</guid><description>Hi , I am writting short steps about how to install latest gdal version in your debian stable. By the time I am writting this post the default version of gdal available in the stable debian bookworm is 3.6.5 but I want the latest one . Usually gdal will publish the latest release in the unstable source first. if you wanna get your hand on it either you need to install it from the source or you can install it from the unstable source. I will list how to install from unstable source only for the gdal</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Share Postgresql from Windows to WSL Linux</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/share-postgresql-port-wsl/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/share-postgresql-port-wsl/</guid><description>I am writting this short tutorial about how to share your  current postgresql with postgis extension installed in your windows system with WSL. We will use networking share method.  For me , I needed to Install postgersql on my harddisk and I had it already before installing WSL and in need of sharing . I am documenting the steps you can take if you wanna download and install it in windows</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Working with open imagery of the world ? Upload your images in OpenAerialMap </title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/upload-in-openaerialmap/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/upload-in-openaerialmap/</guid><description>OpenAerialMap is an open service to provide access to a commons of openly licensed imagery and map layer services. Download or contribute imagery to the growing commons of openly licensed imagery. This short tutorial will document the steps needed to process and publish your images in OpenAerialMap.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monitor GPU Usage in WSL debian</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/monitor-gpu-in-wsl/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/monitor-gpu-in-wsl/</guid><description>In the competitive world of front-end development, a strong portfolio is your ticket to showcasing your skills, making a lasting impression on potential employers or clients, and advancing your career. Your portfolio is your digital business card, and it should be a reflection of your talent, creativity, and expertise.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Segment Anything (SAM) and OpenStreetMap (OSM)</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/sam-and-osm/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/sam-and-osm/</guid><description>The purpose of this research document is to explore the possibilities of the Segment Anything Model (SAM) [Segment Anything](https://github.com/facebookresearch/segment-anything)  developed by Meta in OpenStreetMap mapping. SAM is a promising model in the field of image segmentation, and its potential application to fAIr could enable the tracing of various features on maps. This document provides an overview of SAM&apos;s working mechanism, test cases conducted with SAM, and two potential integration ideas for utilizing SAM</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Install Debian in Different Location -WSL Windows</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/install-debian-in-wsl-windows/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/install-debian-in-wsl-windows/</guid><description>I was trying to install Debian in different location rather than the C drive . Sharing the steps I took .</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OSM - Stats , A automatic Bot for twitter</title><link>https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/osm-stats-bot/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://kshitijrajsharma.github.io/blog/osm-stats-bot/</guid><description>I want to share the information about that I have created two OpenStreetMap Bot on Twitter</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>